# GASEEMA NDUNG'U

I'm a polyglot developer with over 4 years of experience as a software engineer, and have worked at both small startups and large organizations. While I'm a proficient full-stack developer, I'm majorly focused on server side development, but equally inclined to client side development as well.

## personal information

FULL NAME Gaseema Ndung'u

GITHUB @gaseema

**E-MAIL** gaseema.n@gmail.com

PHONE +254 721 882 694

FREELANCE Available

## languages

**ENGLISH** 

• • • • o o fluent

**SWAHILI** 

native

**CHINESE** 

• O O O O O O beginner

## professional skills

- F HTML 5 & CSS 3
- JavaScript & jQuery
- NodeJs
- Express Js
- MongoDB

Nginx

- Wordpress
- Github

## additional skills

- Operating systems: Windows, Unix, Linux
- Database systems: SQL Server, MySQL
- Agile Development
- Adobe Photoshop

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

2017 - 2018

**Bitsoko** Software Developer Bitsoko is a point of sale terminal that creates open-source mobile services for micro, small and medium enterprises.

### **ROLES**

- Analyzing user requirements
- Writing and testing code, refining and rewriting it as necessary
- Researching, designing and writing new software programs
- Developing existing programs by analyzing and identifying areas for modification
- Integrating existing software products and getting incompatible platforms to work together
- Maintaining systems by monitoring and correcting software defects
- Working closely with other staff, such as project managers, graphic artists, UX designers, other developers, systems analysts and sales and marketing professionals
- Consulting clients and colleagues concerning the maintenance and performance of software systems with a view to writing or modifying current operating systems
- Continually updating technical knowledge and skills by attending in-house and external courses, reading manuals and accessing new applications.
- Document and demonstrate solutions by developing documentation, flowcharts, layouts, diagrams, charts, code comments and clear code

2016 - 2017

### Kenya Industrial & Allied Safety Services

Frontend Engineer

Kenya Industrial & Allied Safety Services is the leading company in elevator statutory inspection as well providing proactive IT strategy, systems design and ongoing support to streamline your business operations, increasing productivity and boosting profitability.

#### **ROLES**

- Develop new user-facing features
- Build reusable code and libraries for future use
- Ensure the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs
- Optimize application for maximum speed and scalability
- Assure that all user input is validated before submitting to backend

2016 - 2017

Collaborate with other team members and stakeholder

### Moringa School Resident Hacker

Moringa School's mission is to transform higher education throughout Africa and enable its graduates to be globally competitive with their peers. Developing future knowledge workers through market-driven education.

### **ROLES**

- Curriculum development
- I was a curriculum instructor mainly frontend developement
- Conducting interviews to applicants
- Reviewed code written by students

# **EDUCATION**

Moringa School Mobile & Web Development

# **INTERESTS**



Animals



Travel



Bicycle



**Parties** 



Swimming



Coffee